ILGWU. Newspapers, 5780/125
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Newspapers
1913-1980
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/125
1.5 cubic feet
3 linear feet
Publications
This collection consists of publications either produced or collected by the ILGWU. It includes periodicals of local unions, joint boards, and the international periodicals, as well as publications from other organizations.
5516871
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
July 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, July 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of publications either produced or collected by the ILGWU. It includes periodicals of local unions, joint boards, and the international periodicals, as well as publications from other organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780 PUBS. ILGWU publications
5780/125 G. ILGWU. Photographs and ad boards
General
"Permanent deposit"
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States
5516871
- Der Arbeter Kamf, 1930-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Yiddish; The Workers' Struggle; published by the Communist Party of the United States
- Bulletin (Box 1, Folder 2)
  English and Yiddish. Issued by the Progressive Group of the ILGWU
- Calling All Shops, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Dressmakers' General Strike Bulletin no.1 (1936:Feb. 7)
- Dress Bulletin, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  v.1:no.2 (1932:July). Official Organ of the Allied Dress Manufacturers Association.
- Dos Freie Wort, 1926-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Yiddish; The Free Word; published by the Group of Cloakmakers, ILGWU
- The I.L.G.er, 1946-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  v.2:no.7 (1946:Aug./Sep.); v.14:no.3 (1960:Summer).
- In Kampf, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Yiddish; In Struggle; v.1:no.3 (1926:Dec.); published by the New York Joint Board Furriers Union
- The Ladies' Garment Cutter, 1913-1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  v.1:no.4-5 (1913); v.2:no.12,48-49 (1914); v.3:no.4,6-7,13-15,27,29-31 (1915); v.4:no.15 (1916); v.5:no.7 (1917)
- The Ladies' Garment Worker, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  v.5:no.2 (1953:Dec.); v.6:no.1 (1954:July).
- The Local 22 Dressmaker, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  English and Spanish.
- Local 23-25 News, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  February, 1980
- Local 99 News, 1954-1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  v.1:no.1-3 (1954); v.2:no.2-4 (1957); v.6:no.2 (1959); v.11:no.1,5-6 (1965); v.12:no.1 (1966)
- Local 105 Reports, 1953-1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  v.5:no.1 (1953:Mar.); v.5:no.3 (1955:Sep.); April 1961.
- Monatlakher Idisher Buletin, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Yiddish; Monthly Jewish Bulletin; published by the Community Party of the United States
- The Needle Worker, 1924-1933 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  English and Yiddish. v.1:no.4 (1924); v.2:no.6 (1931); v.3:no.6-8 (1932); Dressmakers Bulletin no.1 (1933)
- The New Post, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Yiddish. v.1:no.1-5,7-8 (1927); v.1:no.10-11 (1928).
- Nineteen Twenty-Three, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  English and Yiddish. v.1:no.1 (1922). Jobbers Edition.
- Pennsylvania Labor Record, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  v.11:no.33 (1943:Dec.)
- Progresiver Dresmaker, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  English and Yiddish. v.1:no.1 (No Date); v.1 (1934); v.1:no.1-2 (1935)
- Der Progresiver Kapn un Milinery Arbeter, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Yiddish; The Progressive Caps and Millinery Workers; published by the Caps and Millinery Workers Section of the Trade Union Educational League
- The Progressive Unionist, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  English and Yiddish. v.1:no.1-4 (1936)
- Sew-Sew News, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  v.1:no.7 (1940:May); v.1:no.8 (1940:Oct).
- The Shipping Clerk, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  v.5:no.2 (1957:June).
- Shop News, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  English and Spanish. no.6-7,9,20-21 (1941)
- Treyd Yunyon Zenter, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Yiddish; Trade Union Center; v.1:no.1-2 (1930); published by the Trade Center Union Group, Local 1, ILGWU
- The Union Dressmaker, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  English and Yiddish. v.1:no.1-3 (1934)
- Union Vanguard, 1938-1944 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  v.1:no.1-6 (1938); v.2:no.8- 9 (1938); v.3:no.14-15 (1939); v.2:no.21 (1944)
- United Dressmaker, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  English and Yiddish. v.1:no.1 (1935). Campaign Organ of the Left Wing and Active Members Groups.
- Unzer Wort, 1926-1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Yiddish; Our Word; includes Unzer Wort published in Montreal, Quebec, and Unzer Wort, published by the Local 1, United Progressive Trade Union Center
- Workers Age, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Bulletin, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  no.1 (1944:Jan. 2). The Progressive Trade Union Committee.
- The Chicago Needle Worker, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  v.1:no.9 (1928:Apr.)
- The Cutter, 1926-1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The Dress Presser, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  English and Yiddish. v.6:no.2 (1942:Mar.)
- Der Dresmaker, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  English and Yiddish. Communist Party. v.1:no.1 (1938:Jan.); v.2:no.1 (1939:Jan.)
- Der Dresmaker, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Yiddish. Dresmaker Welfeyr Klub
- Dressmakers' Bulletin, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Dressmakers! Prepare for the General Strike (Box 2, Folder 8)
  English and Italian. 2 copies
- The Dressmakers' Voice, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  English and Yiddish. v.1:no.2 (1934:Mar. 12)
- Einigkeit, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Yiddish. v.1:no.1-15 (1927:Mar.-July)
- Einigkeit, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Yiddish. V.1:no.16-v.2:no.6 (1927:July-1928:Apr.)
- Gerechtigkeit, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Yiddish. Justice, v.11:no.2 (1929:Jan. 25)
- Hofenung, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  English and Yiddish. v.1:no.1 (1939:Dec.); v.2:no.2 (1940:Feb.)
- Hot Speeches and Wild Talk (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Justice, 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  v.19:no.6 (1937:Mar. 16); v.22:no.7 (1940:Mar. 18)
- Klok Opereytors Buletin, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Yiddish. no.1-2 (1939)
- Der Klouk Finisher, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  English and Yiddish. v.1:no1-5 (1942)
- Klouk-Finishers Shtime, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Yiddish. v.1:no.1 (1942:Jan.)
- Der Klouk un Dresmaker, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Yiddish. v.1:no.1-3 (1931)
- Knitgoods Workers Voice, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  v.30:no.5 (1966:Oct.). 2 copies.
- Konvenshon Buletin, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Labor Unity, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  v.3:no.21 (1929:Aug. 17)
- The Ladies' Garment Cutter, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  v.1:no.11 (1939:May); v.2:no.9 (1940:March); v.2:no.11 (1940:May)
- Let's Teach the Truth About Unions., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Reprinted from American Teacher, March 1942.
- Mode O'Day News, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  no.25 (1942:Feb. 18). 2 copies. V.2:no.26 (1942:Feb. 23)
- Di Naye Welt, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Yiddish. v.8:no.33 (1921:Sep. 16)
- The Needle Worker, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  English, Yiddish, and Spanish. v.1:no.1-2 (1930:Aug.-Oct.); v.2:no.710 (1931:July-Oct.)
- The Newsette, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  v.1:no.1 (1941:Dec.); v.1:no.4 (1942:Jan.)
- Nodl Arbeter, 1924-1927 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Yiddish. v.1:no.2/3 (1924:Feb./Mar.); v.2:no.4 (1926
- Di Nodl-Arbeter Shtime, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Yiddish
- The Organizer (Box 2, Folder 31)
  English and Spanish. v.1:no.1-2,7
- Our Local 66, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  v.6:no.3 (1947:Mar.)
- Progressive Youth, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  June, 1937
- Rank and File Cutter, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  v.3:no.3 (1937:Mar.)
- The Red Needle, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  English and Yiddish. V.1:no.1-4 (1929)
- A Report to the Members: Knitgoods Workers Voice, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Di Rifermaker Shtime (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Safeguard Your Union Against Disruption (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Der Tsentrist, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  Yiddish. v.1:no.1-2 (1929)
- Undzer Yodl (Box 2, Folder 40)
  Yiddish. 2 copies
- The Union Voice (Box 2, Folder 41)
  v.1:no.2
- The Voice of Unity, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  English and Yiddish. v.1:no.1-6 (1928)
- The Word of the Dressmakers, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  English and Italian. v.2:no.3 (1938:May)